<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dian Pan</title>
    <description>a fun little blog about learning to code.</description>
    <link>http://dianpan.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://dianpan.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 17:28:46 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 17:28:46 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Identifying stereotype threats</title>
        <description># Phase 0, Week 6


This week we researched the topic of stereotype threat. Per Wikipedia:

``` Stereotype threat is a situational predicament in which people are or feel themselves to be at risk of confirming negative stereotypes about their social group. ```

I&#39;m sure everyone has felt stereotype threat from time to time. For example, I&#39;m Chinese, my parents are first generation immigrants. They have strong accents, cook traditional Chinese food and don&#39;t behave like American parents. Growing up, I tried desperately to blend in with my classmates. I think Asians suffer from the &quot;model minority&quot; steryotype:

```A model minority is a minority group (whether based on ethnicity, race or religion) whose members are most often perceived to achieve a higher degree of socioeconomic success than the population average. This success is typically measured in income, education, low crime rates and high family stability. The term is highly controversial, for it is sometimes used to suggest there is no need for government action to reduce discrimination. ```

Growing up, I found subtle expectations everywhere pushing me to conform to those model minority steryotypes. For example, there is this belief that Asians are good at math. My parents were great at math, but me... not so much. They didn&#39;t understand why I wasn&#39;t good at math and I questioned it too. Ultimately, concluding that just maybe it&#39;s because I&#39;m not that smart. So imagine if you will, not fitting into you&#39;re own steryotype, that led to some weird identity issues.

To be clear, I don&#39;t think I&#39;m bad at math, I was just way more interested in things like music, reading and writing. But I do think growing up with those fixed beliefs kept me away from STEM majors in college. Which is why, it&#39;s pretty [ironic, funny, awesome] that I am now leaving my nice Marketing gig to pursue code. I think that act in of itself is breaking down some of my own stereotype threats. I&#39;m looking forward to continuing this story once I finish DBC and start a new career in web development!</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://dianpan.github.io/2015-06-22-identifying-stereotype-threatsmarkdown</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dianpan.github.io/2015-06-22-identifying-stereotype-threatsmarkdown</guid>
        
        
        <category>phase0</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Chefs in the kitchen</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;phase-0-week-1&quot;&gt;Phase 0, week 1&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going into DBC, I really didn’t know what to expect with the new hybrid offsite/onsite approach. Now that week 1 is coming to an end, I’ve been really impressed so far with how well thought out and high quality the curriculum is. I’ve learned how to navigate through the command line, push new code onto github, understand version control and get git working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Week 1 has also been eye opening, I didn’t realize how much time Phase 0 actually took, and I need to make sure I don’t short change myself by not dedicating enough time to all of the material.  DBC claims that you can hold a full time job while going through Phase 0 but I disagree.  I think it’s better to hold a part time job and focus on really learning to material in Phase 0.  [ &lt;em&gt;Update&lt;/em&gt; : I quit my job around Week 6 to focus soley on DBC]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve enjoyed every single Shereef video I’ve seen so far, and this one was no exception. He brings up 2 important topics that hit home:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He talks about a restaurant vs kitchen approach. A restaurant mindset is the idea that I paid for DBC, so I’m owed a certain outcome or experience. I find myself with the restaurant approach a lot. I work hard for my money so I expect to get what I pay for. The danger of that belief is that I become entitled but powerless. I cease control of my experience rather than own it. The other mindset is the kitchen approach, where we see ourselves as chefs in the kitchen, creating things together with DBC. The kitchen mindset is powerful because I start owning my education rather than giving that ownership to DBC.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The second topic I struggle with is dealing with fear. Fear that everyone in your cohort will be better than you and fear that you are far better than your cohort and they’ll drag you down. The best part of the video is when Shereef puts things in perspective, he says the difference between someone brand new and someone with more experience is very small.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2015 15:08:40 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://dianpan.github.io/cultural-post-chefs-in-kitchen</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dianpan.github.io/cultural-post-chefs-in-kitchen</guid>
        
        
        <category>phase0</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>An intro to git, Github, and the command line</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;phase-0-week-1&quot;&gt;Phase 0, week 1&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Week 1 covered 3 main topics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;git&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Github&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the command line&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like most things I don’t understand, I was really intimidated with Github, this public arena to show off your code. I always assumed that git and Github were related. This week I got a crash course on git and Github 101 and am forking repos, creating branches and merging like a pro. So what is the difference between git and GitHub?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;git lives locally on your computer while GitHub is an online platform where you can share your repositories and updated code pushes with other people. It keeps a working version of your code that you can share publicly with others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s 2 main reasons why Github is so powerful:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Version control - version control means keeping track of all of your changes to a specific file, project, etc. through making copies of said file throughout each change. Github is a nice place to keep all of those versions in one place, where you or others can access all of the past and current version.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Developers use version control to hedge against mistakes and lost work. If a mistake is made, they can go back to a bug free, working version of their code. It saves time and money and makes perfect sense to me. I wish I had started using git for my own work. I’ve written over my email code many times before. I save different files locally on my computer, and its a mess to sort through.
Branching - branching allows you to create clones of your files that you can work on independent of each other. Once you’re satisfied with a piece of your code, you can then merge it back to the main or “master” branch. This allows for many people to work on the same project without having to coordinate with each other or stepping on each other’s toes.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 15:08:40 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://dianpan.github.io/intro-to-git-github</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dianpan.github.io/intro-to-git-github</guid>
        
        
        <category>phase0</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
